[
  {
    "question": "Art historians will generally focus on all of the following contexts of an artwork EXCEPT",
    "a": "cultural",
    "b": "social",
    "c": "historical",
    "d": "logical",
    "e": "economic",
    "correct_answer": "d"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is aesthetics?",
    "a": "an inquiry into the value of an artwork",
    "b": "a method of understanding art through contextual information",
    "c": "a study of humanity concerned with human culture and society",
    "d": "a philosophical inquiry into the nature and expression of beauty",
    "e": "the classification of artistic styles",
    "correct_answer": "d"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following fields is NOT considered fine art?",
    "a": "printing",
    "b": "pottery",
    "c": "painting",
    "d": "architecture",
    "e": "drawing",
    "correct_answer": "b"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which branch of analysis focuses on the visual qualities of the artwork itself?",
    "a": "biographical analysis",
    "b": "formal analysis",
    "c": "sensory analysis",
    "d": "critical analysis",
    "e": "aesthetic analysis",
    "correct_answer": "b"
  },
  {
    "question": "When performing contextual analysis, art historians will generally NOT examine",
    "a": "patronage and ownership",
    "b": "other artworks during the era",
    "c": "cost of the artwork",
    "d": "the use of space in the painting",
    "e": "viewer access",
    "correct_answer": "d"
  },
  {
    "question": "When did art history arise as an academic discipline?",
    "a": "20th century",
    "b": "1st century",
    "c": "16th century",
    "d": "18th century",
    "e": "9th century",
    "correct_answer": "d"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following art historians shifted away from individual biographical analysis to a study of stylistic developments?",
    "a": "Giorgio Vasari",
    "b": "Pliny the Elder",
    "c": "Johann Winckelmann",
    "d": "Robert Smithson",
    "e": "Michael Heizer",
    "correct_answer": "c"
  },
  {
    "question": "For what is Giorgio Vasari MOST famous?",
    "a": "restoring Greco-Roman art",
    "b": "writing the first art criticism",
    "c": "gathering biographies of great Italian artists",
    "d": "contributing to color theory",
    "e": "expanding the scope of art history",
    "correct_answer": "c"
  },
  {
    "question": "From where did Pliny the Elder come?",
    "a": "ancient Greece",
    "b": "post-war U.S.",
    "c": "modern France",
    "d": "ancient Rome",
    "e": "medieval England",
    "correct_answer": "d"
  },
  {
    "question": "Who contributed to the developing concept of artistic genius?",
    "a": "Petrine Archer-Straw",
    "b": "Franz Kugler",
    "c": "Raphael Sanzio",
    "d": "Giorgio Vasari",
    "e": "Alfred Sisley",
    "correct_answer": "d"
  },
  {
    "question": "The meaning of a work of art is NOT",
    "a": "dependent on where the artwork is located",
    "b": "subject to change over time",
    "c": "revealed through the visual aspects of the piece",
    "d": "defined purely by the artist’s intention",
    "e": "open to different interpretations",
    "correct_answer": "d"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is a reason art historians might depend on reproductions?",
    "a": "Original artworks are too valuable to use for studying art history.",
    "b": "Reproductions are more detailed than originals.",
    "c": "Reproductions are more popular with the general public.",
    "d": "Original artworks are damaged or lost.",
    "e": "Reproductions are easier to study with computerized tools.",
    "correct_answer": "d"
  },
  {
    "question": "How has the practice of art history changed MOST over the years?",
    "a": "It has eliminated bias from most forms of criticism.",
    "b": "It has incorporated more technical analysis.",
    "c": "It has encompassed a wider variety of art.",
    "d": "It has become more concerned with the economic aspects of art.",
    "e": "It has largely ceased to focus on aesthetics.",
    "correct_answer": "c"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is an example of a previously dismissed craft that art historians might now include in their studies?",
    "a": "film",
    "b": "textiles",
    "c": "television shows",
    "d": "architecture",
    "e": "posters",
    "correct_answer": "b"
  },
  {
    "question": "Who commissioned the paintings on the ceiling of the Sistine Chapel?",
    "a": "Louis XI",
    "b": "the House of Wessex",
    "c": "Ivan III",
    "d": "the House of Medici",
    "e": "Pope Julius II",
    "correct_answer": "e"
  },
  {
    "question": "Johann Joachim Winckelmann shifted away from Giorgio Vasari’s biographical emphasis, instead focusing on",
    "a": "subject matter",
    "b": "stylistic development",
    "c": "aesthetic appreciation",
    "d": "historical context",
    "e": "cultural influence",
    "correct_answer": "b"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which northern African country's burial customs and dry climate facilitated the preservation of delicate materials?",
    "a": "Libya",
    "b": "Algeria",
    "c": "Morocco",
    "d": "Sudan",
    "e": "Egypt",
    "correct_answer": "e"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which material was primarily used to create the cave paintings found in Chauvet Cave?",
    "a": "yellow ochre",
    "b": "green pigments",
    "c": "blue ink",
    "d": "red ochre",
    "e": "white chalk",
    "correct_answer": "d"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following styles does Ancient Egyptian art MOST emphasize?",
    "a": "symmetry",
    "b": "linear perspective",
    "c": "hierarchical scale",
    "d": "realism",
    "e": "geometric precision",
    "correct_answer": "c"
  },
  {
    "question": "King Tutankhamun’s burial mask is made of gold and adorned with",
    "a": "sapphires",
    "b": "rubies",
    "c": "ivory",
    "d": "coral",
    "e": "blue glass",
    "correct_answer": "e"
  },
  {
    "question": "The Persian Empire was based in what is present-day",
    "a": "Iraq",
    "b": "Armenia",
    "c": "Iran",
    "d": "Afghanistan",
    "e": "Turkey",
    "correct_answer": "c"
  },
  {
    "question": "Who centralized power in the ancient Babylonian civilization and created the oldest known legal code?",
    "a": "Hammurabi",
    "b": "Sargon",
    "c": "Akurduana",
    "d": "Nabopolassar",
    "e": "Gilgamesh",
    "correct_answer": "a"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which ancient Mesopotamian architectural development resulted in the creation of ziggurats?",
    "a": "floating gardens",
    "b": "wall enclosures",
    "c": "underground chambers",
    "d": "platform structures",
    "e": "tented structures",
    "correct_answer": "d"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which famous monument features concentric rings made of sarsen and bluestones?",
    "a": "Avebury",
    "b": "Machu Picchu",
    "c": "Stonehenge",
    "d": "Great Wall of China",
    "e": "Parthenon",
    "correct_answer": "c"
  },
  {
    "question": "The Venus (or Woman) of Willendorf figure is missing",
    "a": "facial features",
    "b": "breasts",
    "c": "the pubic area",
    "d": "arms",
    "e": "feet",
    "correct_answer": "e"
  },
  {
    "question": "Whose would be MOST likely to challenge a book on Renaissance art that features only Leonardo da Vinci, Michelangelo, and Raphael Sanzio?",
    "a": "a feminist historian",
    "b": "an economic historian",
    "c": "an environmental historian",
    "d": "a Marxist historian",
    "e": "a religious historian",
    "correct_answer": "a"
  },
  {
    "question": "All of the following materials prove especially enduring EXCEPT for",
    "a": "stone",
    "b": "marble",
    "c": "wood",
    "d": "metal",
    "e": "fired clay",
    "correct_answer": "c"
  },
  {
    "question": "What have scholars proposed as the most likely purpose of cave paintings?",
    "a": "cultural celebrations",
    "b": "decorative purposes",
    "c": "hunting ceremonies",
    "d": "educational instruction",
    "e": "social gatherings",
    "correct_answer": "c"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which part of Stonehenge marks the point where the sun rises on the midsummer solstice?",
    "a": "heel-stone",
    "b": "altar stone",
    "c": "pillar-stone",
    "d": "capstone",
    "e": "keystone",
    "correct_answer": "a"
  },
  {
    "question": "What kingdom to the south of Egypt is increasingly garnering attention for its significant contributions to art history?",
    "a": "Akkad",
    "b": "Nubia",
    "c": "Assyria",
    "d": "Sumer",
    "e": "Mesopotamia",
    "correct_answer": "b"
  }
]